ABOUT ME

Exposure in the Banking Sector with an overall experience of 3 years. Contributed my efforts in the Compliance as well as Regulatory reporting part of the Bank. My Current and Past roles involved a lot of interaction with the Internal Stakeholders of the Bank including the Senior Management and the Regulatory Authorities such as RBI. So it has helped me to develop good interpersonal skills.

I am seeking a challenging opportunity with an Organisation that would be mutually beneficial to both myself and my employer and allow for future growth and advancement.

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH

HINDI

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of birth 01/06/1996

Nationality Indian

Marital status Single

NARENDRASINGH RATHOD

MANAGER, COMPLIANCE UNIT



A-603, Krishna Residency, Murbad Road, Near State Bank of India Branch, Shahad, Kalyan, 421301, India



8308047243



nrathod106@gmail.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

YES BANK LTD.

Mumbai Sep 2019 - Present

Manager, Compliance Unit

- 1. Responsible for the timely submission of the Onsite and Offsite data / information requirements of Reserve Bank of India (RBI) and ensuring responses to the RBI Inspection report are collated in a timely manner.
- 2. To enables efficient conduct of Onsite Inspection conducted by RBI, usually for a period of 3 to 4 months, including timely submission of data / information to RBI.
- 3. Effective handling of Preliminary Risk Assessment Report (PRAR) Risk Assessment Report (RAR) Proposed Risk Mitigation Plan (PRMP) and Risk Mitigation Plan reports issued by the RBI. Collating and reviewing the responses to the observations in the PRAR, RAR, PRMP and RMP.
- 4. Collating and reviewing the Quarterly Submissions of Tranche1, Tranche 1A, 1B, 1C, 1D, 1E, 1F & 1G data and Annual Submission of Tranche II, III and Bank Profile Return to RBI.
- Performing the Variance Analysis for the Tranche points of different Tranche returns and collating & reviewing the explanations / responses from different Internal Stakeholders of the Bank.
- 6. Effectively participating in the Automation of various tranche returns submitted to RBI.
- 7. Liaises regularly and effectively with RBI Officials for resolution of queries raised by the stakeholders in the Bank with respect to various RBI submissions.
- 8. Ensures timely submission of adhoc information request received from RBI Inspection Team after review of the information.

HDFC BANK LTD.

Mumbai Nov 2017 - Aug 2019

Manager, Regulatory Reporting for Foreign Branch Operations

- 1. Responsible for timely submission of Regulatory Returns for Overseas Branches of the Bank in accordance with the guidelines of Regulatory Authority such as Hong Kong Monetary Authority & Reserve Bank of India.
- 2. Liaising with various departments like Credit Administration, Compliance, Treasury Operation, Treasury Mid Office, Finance for compilation and preparation of returns.
- 3. Ensuring the proper automation of returns to add more efficiency in the process.
- 4. Preparation of Risk-Based Supervision (RBS) Returns pertaining to the Foreign Branch Operations of Bank.
- Exposure to the SWIFT system and preparation of various SWIFT messages.

ATTAR & CO.

Mumbai

Articled Assistant

Oct 2014 - Oct 2017

- 1. Experience in the fields of Accountancy, Auditing, Taxation & Financial Reporting of Listed Company, Private Limited Company, Partnership Firms & Individuals.
- 2. Handling the Concurrent Audit of a Co-Operative Bank.
- 3. Preparation of Income Tax computation of Individual, Firms and Companies
- 4. Handling various other Tax & Accounts related work.

EDUCATION

THE INSTITUTE OF CHARTERED ACCOUNTANTS OF INDIA

Mumbai 2017

Chartered Accountant

- Cleared CPT (June 2013), IPCC (May 2014) & CA Final (May 2017) in first attempt with the percentage score of 59.12% in CA Final
- 2. Good learning of subjects covering different areas such as Accountancy, Finance, Taxation, etc.

CFA INSTITUTE

Mumbai 2021

CFA Level III

- 1. Cleared my CFA Level I (December 2018) and CFA Level II (June 2019) in first attempt.
- 2. Pursuing CFA Level III (May 2021).
- 3. Good knowledge of Finance concepts.

B. K. BIRLA COLLEGE OF ARTS, SCIENCE & COMMERCE

Kalyan 2016 B. Com

SKILLS

CONDUCTING RISK ASSESSMENTS REVIEWING RECORDS

TIME MANAGEMENT SKILLS EXCELLENT COMMUNICATION

RELATIONSHIP DEVELOPMENT QUICK LEARNER